<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Oli&#39;s Workshop</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Oli&#39;s Workshop</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 27 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Defining Reliability within Your System</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/definingreliability/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/definingreliability/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This outline provides an approach to building reliability into your system or application. To fully grasp the concepts discussed here, it’s essential to understand the concepts discussed in the other articles in this collection, as they serve as foundational building blocks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;understanding-business-requirements-and-user-expectation&#34;&gt;Understanding Business Requirements and User Expectation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before diving deep into the actual system, we must gain a deeper understanding of what is expected of our application.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;build-what-you-need-not-what-you-think-you-need&#34;&gt;Build what you need not what you think you need&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Speak with the development teams, platform engineers, and business stakeholders to understand our critical business objectives.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Determine what our users expect, at minimum, from our application. Don&amp;rsquo;t focus on anything that isn&amp;rsquo;t identified as important to the business or user&amp;rsquo;s of the application.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Identify critical user journeys.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Map out primary functions (user journeys) that directly impact customer satisfaction and business objectives. This is application specific.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Clarify our objectives and Key Performance Indicators.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Are we aiming for high availability? What exactly does that look like?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Setting these goals helps inform our SLO benchmarks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;defining-whats-important&#34;&gt;Defining What&amp;rsquo;s Important&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order for development teams to identify and define SLOs and SLIs, they (and you) must understand what they are. Below is a short introduction.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Establishing Reliability, a High Level Overview</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/establishingreliability/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/establishingreliability/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is the first in a collection of articles which work together as a guideline for establishing Reliability and Observability within a system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note:&lt;/strong&gt; Below, I refer to applications, services, and the system as a whole. In a microservice-based architecture, all the individual services work together to create the overall application that an end-user interacts with. This context should help clarify some of the explanations that follow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;questions-to-ask&#34;&gt;Questions to Ask&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Are all services within the system observable?
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Are we using a well-known framework or standard? (i.e. OpenTelemetry)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How do we configure our Infrastructure?
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;IaC or manual config?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Can we identify any areas we may want to measure based on configuration?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Have all previous outage causes or potential issues been identified and fixed?
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If these above have not been fixed are they properly documented and work tracked?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is there tech debt to consider?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;understand-your-needs&#34;&gt;Understand Your Needs&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are building reliability and observability into a system, it is most important to lean on the SMEs from your development teams and platform engineering teams. They are the people who understand the system you are to measure.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Instrumentation with OpenTelemetry</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/introtoopentelemetry/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/introtoopentelemetry/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;opentelemetry---an-overview&#34;&gt;OpenTelemetry - An Overview&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OTEL is an open source observability framework. It offers vendor-agnostic or vendor-neutral APIs, software development kits (SDKs) and other tools for collecting telemetry data from cloud-native applications and their supporting infrastructure to understand their performance and health.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It standardizes the way telemetry data is collected and transmitted to our backend platforms. With a common format for instrumentation used across our services, we avoid gaps in visibility.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Monitoring &amp; Observability, An Introduction</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/introtomonitoringandobservability/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/introtomonitoringandobservability/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-monitoring&#34;&gt;What &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;is&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; Monitoring?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The action you take. We monitor a system, an application, a metric to find anomalies that may indicate a problem. Monitoring allows us to determine whether our system is working correctly and exhibiting expected behaviors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;types-of-monitoring&#34;&gt;Types of Monitoring&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Availability Monitoring &amp;amp; Site Reliability Monitoring - Most often associated with uptime. I touch on these concepts in this &lt;a href=&#34;https://notsuoholi.github.io/posts/srecore/#monitoring--alerting&#34;&gt;post&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/introtomonitoringandobservability/#application-performance-monitoring&#34;&gt;Application Performance Monitoring&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/introtomonitoringandobservability/#synthetic-and-real-user-monitoring&#34;&gt;RUM and Synthetic Monitoring&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Security Monitoring &amp;amp; Network Monitoring - Threat detection and security event management. I won&amp;rsquo;t go into much detail on that for this series but you can begin to read more &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.splunk.com/en_us/blog/learn/security-monitoring.html&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;monitoring-tools&#34;&gt;Monitoring Tools&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Observational - These can be hardware, software, and/or services which report on their operational status.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Analysis - We use these to determine where and why problems are occurring in our system.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There are several tools which allow us to accomplish the above such as Prometheus, Grafana, Tempo, Datadog,  Elasticsearch, Logstash, and Kibana, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;monitoring-challenges&#34;&gt;Monitoring Challenges&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following challenges are often associated with traditional monitoring.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Telemetry, An Introduction</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/intrototelemetry/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/intrototelemetry/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-telemetry&#34;&gt;What &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;is&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; Telemetry?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The process of collecting and analyzing data from various sources to gain insights into our system&amp;rsquo;s overall performance. It&amp;rsquo;s critical to our decision making process and helps us with monitoring and measuring the observability of our system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;telemetry-vs-monitoring&#34;&gt;Telemetry vs Monitoring&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Monitoring has a much narrower focus. The main objective one has for monitoring a system is to detect for potential issues and determine which actions to take to avoid or resolve incidents and escalations. Typical measures include metrics for resource usage and networking activity.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Troubleshooting as an SRE</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/sretroubleshooting/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/sretroubleshooting/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Below, I will outline some of best practices an SRE should follow to efficiently diagnose and resolve issues within a system, even one they are not familiar with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;general-troubleshooting-method&#34;&gt;General Troubleshooting Method&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;1-the-problem-report&#34;&gt;1. The Problem Report&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A problem is reported, whether by alert, customer reported ticket, or complaint/report in internal messaging service (i.e. Slack, MS Teams).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What does this problem report tell us about the expected behavior of the service? What does it tell us about the &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;actual&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; behavior of the service at present.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Security and YOU (the SRE)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/sresecurity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/sresecurity/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Though it may seem as though security might not need to be at the forefront of an SRE&amp;rsquo;s mind, the reality couldn&amp;rsquo;t be more different.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Downtime Reduction - If build security into our practices, we will deliver a product with very few vulnerabilities which in turn means less vulnerability to exploit, and therefore less downtime.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Compliance Standards - In order to meet compliance standards like &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.getkisi.com/guides/soc-2-type-ii#soc-2-type-ii-compliance&#34;&gt;SOC 2&lt;/a&gt;, our in built procedures regarding security must be strong.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No Damage to Brand - If we are breached, our reputation will be damaged, thus degrading consumer trust in our product.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;most-common-threats-relevant-to-sre&#34;&gt;Most Common Threats Relevant to SRE&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;DDoS Attacks - Aims to drive an overwhelming amount of simulated traffic to a service of piece of a service in order to cause it to be unavailable for use by normal end users.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Software exploits - If there is an issue or vulnerability in a specific version of our product or a service we use within our product this could be used by an attacker to gain access to our service or infrastructure.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Phishing - Social engineering can be used to get employees to give up sensitive information and gain access to our service and infrastructure.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ransomware - Gaining access to a piece of our infrastructure or codebase as using this as a means to demand payment.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;best-practices-for-mitigating-threats&#34;&gt;Best Practices for Mitigating Threats&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;access-control&#34;&gt;Access Control&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Controlling access to resources must be a priority.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SRE, Core Principles</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/srecore/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/srecore/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have outlined a few of the core responsibilities and practices of Site Reliability Engineers (SREs).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My goal was to cover key topics like system reliability, incident management, the importance of SLIs, SLOs, and SLAs, and how SREs use monitoring and alerting to maintain service performance while collaborating closely with development teams to ensure scalable, predictable, and efficient systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;sre---a-focus-operational-resilience--toil-reduction&#34;&gt;SRE - A Focus Operational Resilience &amp;amp; TOIL Reduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SREs focus on system reliability and incident management. We make data driven decisions which benefit the system. We automate to reduce toil and improve change management to ensure processes in place are repeatable, predictable, and most importantly, scalable.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DevOps &amp; Release Management, Core Principles</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/devopscore/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/devopscore/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The below serves to outline some of the key aspects of DevOps and Release Engineering. It is not at all a complete guide but does cover some of the most important components. I will add to is as I continue to dive deeper.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;devops---a-delicate-balance-of-development-and-operations&#34;&gt;DevOps - A delicate balance of development and operations.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A focus on continuous delivery and automation in the software development lifecycle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Champion guidelines, practices, and culture that aims  to break down the silos which traditionally separate development, operations, networking, and security.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
