<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Pages on Oli&#39;s Workshop</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/pages/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Pages on Oli&#39;s Workshop</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 27 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/pages/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Building for Reliability, A Series</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/pages/reliability/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/pages/reliability/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Below are a collection of articles which work together as a guideline for establishing Reliability and Observability within a system. Below are links to the articles in this series.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/establishingreliability/&#34;&gt;Establishing Reliability&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/intrototelemetry/&#34;&gt;Telemetry, An Introduction&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/introtoopentelemetry/&#34;&gt;Instrumentation with OpenTelemetry&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/introtomonitoringandobservability/&#34;&gt;Monitoring &amp;amp; Observability, An Introduction&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/definingreliability/&#34;&gt;Defining Reliability within Your System&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SRE VS DevOps</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/pages/srevsdevops/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/pages/srevsdevops/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The distinction between Site Reliability Engineering (SRE) and DevOps often sparks debate within the tech community, as both aim to enhance software delivery and operational efficiency but do so through different principles and methodologies. In this series, I will explore the key concepts of each specialty, highlighting their unique roles and responsibilities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/srecore/&#34;&gt;SRE and Core Principles&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/sresecurity/&#34;&gt;Security and YOU (the SRE)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/sretroubleshooting/&#34;&gt;Troubleshooting as an SRE&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/devopscore/&#34;&gt;DevOps &amp;amp; Release Management, Core Principles&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Background</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/pages/background/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Oct 2024 21:35:26 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/pages/background/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;my-background&#34;&gt;My Background&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am a Site Reliability Engineer with over five years of experience. I have a proven track record of transforming cloud infrastructure, ensuring system reliability, and reducing infrastructure costs. I crave a challenging environment where I can think out of the box and employ new techniques to solve difficult problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;teamsnap&#34;&gt;TeamSnap&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Site Reliability Engineer | Jan 2024 - Present&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Implemented cluster over-provisioning and container image preloading strategies for Kubernetes. Enabling preemptive scaling, image caching, and significant application performance improvements.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Migrated applications from outdated, un-managed GKE clusters to up to date Kubernetes infrastructure on Google Cloud.
Authored and implemented guidelines for zero-downtime node upgrades and failover procedures for GKE clusters.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Established new monitoring baselines for core applications. Developed Datadog Powerpacks for commonly used metrics. Created reusable templates for monitors and dashboards in Terraform.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Developed request-based monitors based on metrics from GKE’s built-in Prometheus to better monitor variations in traffic for critical applications.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Authored comprehensive documentation for services, providing guidance for engineering teams.
Designed and facilitated technical interviews for prospective SRE candidates, assessing their skills and team fit.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Leveraged AI tools to accelerate coding projects, including automated code generation, debugging, and optimization, resulting in improved development efficiency and reduced time to deployment.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;moodys-analytics--passfort-ltd&#34;&gt;Moody&amp;rsquo;s Analytics | Passfort Ltd&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Site Reliability Engineer | Dec 2021 - Jan 2024&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/pages/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Oct 2024 20:53:44 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/pages/about/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am a driven professional constantly trying to find new ways to improve. I understand that a person can only grow when they take time to water themselves. When one pours effort and time into the things that bring them joy and a sense of pride, the result is often seen, felt, and heard by others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My hope is that this simple blog will inspire others to begin that journey for themselves. Here is where I will showcase all the things I am working on, the things that bring me joy, the things that make me better.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
